Guide to the Samir Farid Collection AD.MC.011
Akkasah: Center for Photography (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Samir Farid Collection
1937-1987
Akkasah: Center for Photography (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Farid, Samir, Mr.
AD.MC.011
23
49 Paige boxes 49 negative boxes containing circa 3,000 negatives.
The Samir Farid Collection consists of over 3000 images from Egypt bought from various photographic studios and individual photographers and their private collections. The negatives include images from 265 Egyptian films produced between 1937-1988. Samir Farid (December 1, 1943 – April 4, 2017) was an Egyptian writer and a world renowned film critic, journalist and film historian based in Cairo. He authored and/or translated over 60 books since 1966 on Egyptian, Arab and World cinema. He was the consultant for Cinema Affairs in the Bibliotheca Alexandrina. (2001-2016). He was a jury member of in a number of international film festivals since 1972. (Among them Oberhausen Film Festival 1978, DOC Leipzig Film festival 1984, Annecy International Animated Film Festival 1998, Torino Film Festival 2001, Controcorrente (Upstream section) of Venice Film Festival 2003, Thessaloniki Film Festival 2003 and Taormina Film Festival 2010.) He also was the Head of The Cairo International Film Festival 2014.
Samir Farid Collection description
The Samir Farid Collection from Egypt consists of over 3000 bought from various photographic studios and individual photographers and their private collections. The negatives include images from 265 Egyptian films produced between 1937-1988.
Biography
Samir Farid (December 1, 1943 – April 4, 2017) was an Egyptian writer and a world renowned film critic, journalist and film historian based in Cairo. He authored and/or translated over 60 books since 1966 on Egyptian, Arab and World cinema. He was the consultant for Cinema affairs in the Bibliotheca Alexandrina. (2001-2016).
He was a member of jury in International film festivals since 1972. (Among them Oberhausen Film Festival 1978, DOC Leipzig Film festival 1984, Annecy International Animated Film Festival 1998, Torino Film Festival 2001, Controcorrente (Upstream section) of Venice Film Festival 2003,[1] Thessaloniki Film Festival 2003 and Taormina Film Festival 2010.)
He also was the Head of The Cairo International Film Festival 2014.
Arrangement
The Samir Farid Collection was received in non-archival business envelopes, many with glassine windows that had been damaged by the decomposition of the negatives held within. The negatives were rehoused in four-flap negative glass plate folders, and the information written in english on each envelope was transferred to the new folders. In addition, a folder from each film series was retained with the original arabic handwriting text for later translation.
No documentation was received with reference to the numerical cataloguing system on the original envelopes, and no order could be found that corresponded with any of the known features of the negatives or the films they represented.
Once identified and accurately dated, the negatives were re-ordered according to year, and alphabetically by title within each year.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to original negatives restricted to Akkasah/NYUADSC staff. Materials are fragile and potential for damage from handling is high.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Samir Farid Collection was purchased directly from the film scholar Samir Farid in November of 2015.
Scope and Contents
The Samir Farid Collection consists of over 3,300 photo negatives taken on the sets of egyptian films between 1937 and 1987. The original contexts of the photographs are unknown, but given the composition and subject matter, it can be inferred that the photographs were intended for publicity for the films, actors appearing in the films, and perhaps subjects for cinema posters.
The images include both 'black and white' and 'color' images shot on a variety of film formats. Film brands identified include Kodak Gravure Copy, Kodak Safety, Kodak Panchro Press, Kodak Super XX, Agfa Safety, Ansco Safety Isopan, Ansco Commercial Orthochromatic, Gevaert Safety, Gevaert Panochromatic, Ferrania, and Orwo.
The photographs were shot on the sets in the midst of filming, or between scenes, therefore some of the images are documentary and others posed. It would appear that few if any are candid images. Most photographs are of actors appearing in the films, most notably Omar Sharif, Shadia, Ismail Yasin, Kamal El Shennawy, Mahmoud El Meleigy, Serag Mounir, Samia Gamal, Taheyya Kariokka, Wedad Hamdy, Hussein Riad, Hagar Hamdy, Farid Shawqi, Amina Rizk, Abdelsalam El Nabolsi, and Ahmed Allam.
Some images can be identified as having been taken during filming scenes in the final cut of the film, as precise context can be identified when comparing the photographs to the films themselves. In other cases, the photographs were taken during filming shots that were not used in the final version of the film or were posed in a tableau vivant.
Negative Images; Films; Cinema; Egypt; Actors; Costumes; Performing Arts
- Leila Daughter of the Desert, 1937; ref1; Hafidh, Bahiga, (1908-1983)
  - Leila Daughter of the Desert, 1937; ref1_000001; Hafidh, Bahiga, (1908-1983); 1 negatives (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Leila Daughter of the Desert, 1937; ref1_000002; Hafidh, Bahiga, (1908-1983); 1 negatives (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Leila Daughter of the Desert, 1937; ref1_000003; Hafidh, Bahiga, (1908-1983); 1 negatives (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Leila Daughter of the Desert, 1937; ref1_000004; Hafidh, Bahiga, (1908-1983); 1 negatives (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Leila Daughter of the Desert, 1937; ref1_000005; Hafidh, Bahiga, (1908-1983); 1 negatives (Box 50, Folder 5)
- Wedding Night Widow ('Armalat laylat alzifaf), 1974; ref2; Bedir, Elsayed
  - Wedding Night Widow ('Armalat laylat alzifaf) | Actors in Image: Zein El Ashmawy, Bader El Den Jamgome, 1974; ref2_000001; Bedir, Elsayed; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Facial Hair; Drinks/Beverages; Negative Images; Actors; Films; Men
  - Wedding Night Widow ('Armalat laylat alzifaf) | Actors in Image: Nahed Sherif, 1974; ref2_000002; Bedir, Elsayed; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Films; Women; Outdoors; Negative Images; Actors; Food
  - Wedding Night Widow ('Armalat laylat alzifaf) | Actors in Image: Nagwa Fouad, Bader El Den Jamgome, 1974; ref2_000003; Bedir, Elsayed; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Actors; Women; Men; Negative Images; Films; Furnishings
  - Wedding Night Widow ('Armalat laylat alzifaf) | Actors in Image: Nagwa Fouad, Kamal El Shennawy, Nahed Sherif, 1974; ref2_000004; Bedir, Elsayed; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Men; Swimming Pools; Women; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Actors; Negative Images; Films; Outdoors; Hotels; Facial Hair; Umbrellas/Parasols; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Swimming
  - Wedding Night Widow ('Armalat laylat alzifaf) | Actors in Image: Nadia Seif El Nasr, Kamal El Shennawy, Ahmed Loxer, Sabri Abdulaziz, 1974; ref2_000005; Bedir, Elsayed; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Men; Facial Hair; Offices; Actors; Women; Negative Images; Films; Furnishings
  - Wedding Night Widow ('Armalat laylat alzifaf) | Actors in Image: Nagwa Fouad, Kamal El Shennawy, Nahed Sherif, 1974; ref2_000006; Bedir, Elsayed; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Actors; Men; Women; Swimming Pools; Outdoors; Negative Images; Films; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Hotels; Umbrellas/Parasols; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Swimming
  - Wedding Night Widow ('Armalat laylat alzifaf) | Actors in Image: Nahed Sherif, 1974; ref2_000007; Bedir, Elsayed; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Actors; Women; Outdoors; Films; Negative Images; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Furnishings; Umbrellas/Parasols; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits
  - Wedding Night Widow ('Armalat laylat alzifaf) | Actors in Image: Nagwa Fouad, 1974; ref2_000008; Bedir, Elsayed; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Women; Men; Actors; Orchestra; Negative Images; Films; Pianos; Violins; Performing Arts; Dancing; Musical Instruments; String Instruments; Costumes
  - Wedding Night Widow ('Armalat laylat alzifaf) | Actors in Image: Nadia Seif El Nasr, Nahed Sherif, 1974; ref2_000009; Bedir, Elsayed; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Women; Negative Images; Actors; Films; Furnishings
  - Wedding Night Widow ('Armalat laylat alzifaf) | Actors in Image: Nadia Seif El Nasr, Mokhtar Amin, 1974; ref2_000010; Bedir, Elsayed; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Women; Actors; Men; Films; Costumes; Negative Images; Clocks/Watches
- Les Miserables (Al Bua'saa'), 1943; ref3; Selim, Kamal
  - Les Miserables (Al Bua'saa') | Actors in Image: Lotfeya Nazmy, Amina Rizk, 1943; ref3_000001; Selim, Kamal; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Men; Women; Actors; Outdoors; Fez/Tarboush; Head Covers/Veils; Films; Negative Images; Facial Hair; Palm Trees; Costumes; Hats
  - Les Miserables (Al Bua'saa') | Actors in Image: Abbas Fares, Hassan Kamel, 1943; ref3_000002; Selim, Kamal; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Men; Films; Turbans; Facial Hair; Hats; Negative Images; Actors; Costumes; Canes/Walking Sticks; Food
  - Les Miserables (Al Bua'saa') | Actors in Image: Abbas Fares, 1943; ref3_000003; Selim, Kamal; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Men; Fez/Tarboush; Costumes; Swords/Knives; Weapons; Actors; Films; Negative Images; Arabic Writing; Hats; Canes/Walking Sticks; Uniforms; Police
  - Les Miserables (Al Bua'saa') | Actors in Image: Abbas Fares, 1943; ref3_000004; Selim, Kamal; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Men; Negative Images; Films; Actors; Costumes; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Facial Hair; Uniforms; Police
  - Les Miserables (Al Bua'saa') | Actors in Image: Abbas Fares, 1943; ref3_000005; Selim, Kamal; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Men; Negative Images; Actors; Films; Costumes; Fez/Tarboush; Turbans; Hats; Food; Facial Hair
  - Les Miserables (Al Bua'saa') | Actors in Image: Fakher Fakher, Samia Gamal, Souad Hussein, Beshara Wakim, 1943; ref3_000006; Selim, Kamal; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Women; Actors; Men; Negative Images; Films; Costumes; Fez/Tarboush; Outdoors; Hats
  - Les Miserables (Al Bua'saa') | Actors in Image: Abbas Fares, 1943; ref3_000007; Selim, Kamal; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Men; Actors; Negative Images; Films; Costumes; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Facial Hair; Drinks/Beverages; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Arabic Writing; Outdoors; Canes/Walking Sticks; Smoking
  - Les Miserables (Al Bua'saa') | Actors in Image: Abbas Fares, 1943; ref3_000008; Selim, Kamal; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Men; Actors; Films; Negative Images; Costumes; Hats; Mirrors; Furnishings
  - Les Miserables (Al Bua'saa') | Actors in Image: Abbas Fares, 1943; ref3_000009; Selim, Kamal; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Boys; Men; Actors; Films; Negative Images; Costumes; Fez/Tarboush; Canes/Walking Sticks; Facial Hair; Arabic Writing; Hats; Street Vendors; Children
  - Les Miserables (Al Bua'saa') | Actors in Image: Amina Rizk, Zinat Sedki, 1943; ref3_000010; Selim, Kamal; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Women; Men; Negative Images; Actors; Films; Costumes; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Street Vendors; Arabic Writing; Newspapers/Magazines
  - Les Miserables (Al Bua'saa') | Actors in Image: Serag Mounir, Amina Rizk, Abbas Fares, 1943; ref3_000011; Selim, Kamal; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Men; Women; Films; Negative Images; Actors; Hospitals; Costumes; Facial Hair; Furnishings
  - Les Miserables (Al Bua'saa') | Actors in Image: Amina Rizk, 1943; ref3_000012; Selim, Kamal; 1 negatives; 94x145 mm (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Women; Men; Costumes; Facial Hair; Negative Images; Actors; Films; Jewelry; Fez/Tarboush
- Dreams of Love, 1945; ref4; Al Jazayerli, Fouad
  - Dreams of Love | Actors in Image: Madiha Yousri, Mohamed Amin, 1945; ref4_000001; Al Jazayerli, Fouad; Salem, Atef; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Men; Women; Jewelry; Films; Costumes; Negative Images; Actors; Furnishings
  - Dreams of Love | Actors in Image: Madiha Yousri, Beshara Wakim, 1945; ref4_000002; Al Jazayerli, Fouad; Salem, Atef; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Women; Men; Negative Images; Actors; Films; Fez/Tarboush; Costumes; Hats
  - Dreams of Love | Actors in Image: Mohamed Amin, Madiha Yousri, 1945; ref4_000003; Al Jazayerli, Fouad; Salem, Atef; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Men; Women; Negative Images; Actors; Films; Jewelry; Costumes; Furnishings
  - Dreams of Love | Actors in Image: Mohamed Amin, Beshara Wakim, Said Abou Bakr, 1945; ref4_000004; Al Jazayerli, Fouad; Salem, Atef; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Men; Actors; Films; Negative Images; Hats; Costumes; Cars/Trucks; Transportation
  - Dreams of Love | Actors in Image: Madiha Yousri, Ismail Yasin, 1945; ref4_000005; Al Jazayerli, Fouad; Salem, Atef; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Men; Women; Negative Images; Films; Actors; Costumes
  - Dreams of Love | Actors in Image: Olwiyya Gamil, Ismail Yasin, Madiha Yousri, Mohamed Amin, 1945; ref4_000006; Al Jazayerli, Fouad; Salem, Atef; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Men; Women; Negative Images; Actors; Films; Costumes; Drinks/Beverages; Hand Fans; Furnishings
  - Dreams of Love | Actors in Image: Hagar Hamdy, Ismail Yasin, 1945; ref4_000007; Al Jazayerli, Fouad; Salem, Atef; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Men; Women; Actors; Films; Negative Images; Costumes; Clocks/Watches; Drinks/Beverages; Jewelry
  - Dreams of Love | Actors in Image: Mohamed Amin, Ismail Yasin, 1945; ref4_000008; Al Jazayerli, Fouad; Salem, Atef; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Men; Actors; Films; Negative Images; Costumes; Outdoors; Palm Trees
- First of the Month, 1945; ref5; Hassan, Abdel Fattah
  - First of the Month | Actors in Image: Hussein Sedky, Faten Hamama, 1945; ref5_000001; Hassan, Abdel Fattah; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Maps; Fez/Tarboush; Schools/Education; Girls; Arabic Writing; Actors; Films; Costumes; Men; Women; Clocks/Watches; Teachers; Negative Images; Hats
  - First of the Month | Actors in Image: Faten Hamama, 1945; ref5_000002; Hassan, Abdel Fattah; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Women; Girls; Actors; Turbans; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Facial Hair; Costumes; Statues/Sculptures; Negative Images; Films; Oud; Men
- The Mother, 1945; ref6; Jamee'i, Omar
  - The Mother | Actors in Image: Amina Rizq, Hussein Riad, 1945; ref6_000001; Jamee'i, Omar; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Food; Men; Women; Actors; Facial Hair; Drinks/Beverages; Negative Images; Films; Costumes; Furnishings
  - The Mother | Actors in Image: Sahid Khalil, Laila Fawzy, 1945; ref6_000002; Jamee'i, Omar; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Men; Women; Actors; Jewelry; Negative Images; Films; Clocks/Watches; Costumes
  - The Mother | Actors in Image: Amina Rizk, Hussein Riad, 1945; ref6_000003; Jamee'i, Omar; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Men; Women; Films; Negative Images; Actors; Facial Hair; Hats; Costumes; Newspapers/Magazines
  - The Mother | Actors in Image: Amina Rizk, Laila Fawzy, 1945; ref6_000004; Jamee'i, Omar; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Women; Actors; Films; Negative Images; Costumes; Head Covers/Veils; Furnishings; Group Portraits
  - The Mother | Actors in Image: Amina Rizk, Zouzou Hamdi El Hakim, 1945; ref6_000005; Jamee'i, Omar; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Women; Actors; Films; Negative Images; Head Covers/Veils; Costumes
  - The Mother | Actors in Image: Amina Rizk, Zouzou Hamdi El Hakim, 1945; ref6_000006; Jamee'i, Omar; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Women; Actors; Films; Negative Images; Head Covers/Veils; Costumes; Gloves
- The Gentle Sex, 1945; ref7; Morsi, Ahmed Kamel
  - The Gentle Sex | Actors in Image: Mohamed Amin, Samia Gamal, 1945; ref7_000001; Morsi, Ahmed Kamel; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Men; Women; Costumes; Arabic Writing; Films; Negative Images; Actors; Boys; Girls; Head Covers/Veils; Children
  - The Gentle Sex | Actors in Image: Mohamed Amin, Beshara Wakim, Madiha Yousri, 1945; ref7_000002; Morsi, Ahmed Kamel; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Men; String Instruments; Actors; Costumes; Women; Fez/Tarboush; Negative Images; Films; Musical Instruments; Furnishings; Hats
  - The Gentle Sex | Actors in Image: Abbas Fares, Elham Hussein, 1945; ref7_000003; Morsi, Ahmed Kamel; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Men; Women; Actors; Films; Negative Images; Costumes; Smoking; Jewelry; Books; Facial Hair; Tobacco pipes; Bow Ties; Paintings
  - The Gentle Sex | Actors in Image: Madiha Yousri, 1945; ref7_000004; Morsi, Ahmed Kamel; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Women; Telephones; Films; Negative Images; Actors; Costumes; Furnishings
  - The Gentle Sex | Actors in Image: Mohamed Amin, Beshara Wakim, 1945; ref7_000005; Morsi, Ahmed Kamel; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Canes/Walking Sticks; Men; Films; Negative Images; Actors; Costumes; Fez/Tarboush; Furnishings; Hats
  - The Gentle Sex | Actors in Image: Elham Hussein, Mohamed Amin, 1945; ref7_000006; Morsi, Ahmed Kamel; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Men; Women; Films; Cigarettes; Drinks/Beverages; Actors; Negative Images; Furnishings
- Angels in Hell, 1946; ref8; Al Imam, Hassan
  - Angels in Hell, 1946; ref8_000001; Al Imam, Hassan; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Men; Women; Negative Images; Films; Actors; Clocks/Watches; Hats; Facial Hair; Costumes; Arabic Writing
  - Angels in Hell | Actors in Image: Elsayed Bedir, 1946; ref8_000002; Al Imam, Hassan; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Men; Women; Negative Images; Films; Cigarettes; Actors; Costumes; Smoking
  - Angels in Hell | Actors in Image: Amina Rizk, Zouzou Shakib, 1946; ref8_000003; Al Imam, Hassan; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 47)
    Women; Actors; Films; Negative Images; Bags/Purses; Costumes; Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings
  - Angels in Hell | Actor in Image: Amina Rizk, 1946; ref8_000004; Al Imam, Hassan; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Negative Images; Women; Films; Actors; Paintings; Pianos; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Telephones; Costumes; Furnishings
  - Angels in Hell | Actors in Image: Elsayed Bedir, Faten Hamama, 1946; ref8_000005; Al Imam, Hassan; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Women; Men; Negative Images; Films; Actors; Girls; Food; Drinks/Beverages; Cigarettes; Smoking; Hats; Costumes; Radios; Furnishings
  - Angels in Hell | Actors in Image: Zouzou Shakib, Serag Mounir, Amina Rizk, 1946; ref8_000006; Al Imam, Hassan; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Men; Women; Negative Images; Actors; Films; Facial Hair; Paintings; Costumes; Fez/Tarboush; Bags/Purses; Jewelry; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Furnishings; Hats
- Bedouins Love, 1946; ref9; Al Jazayerli, Fouad
  - Bedouins Love | Actors in Image: Ismail Yasin, Soad Mekawy, Beshara Wakim, 1946; ref9_000001; Al Jazayerli, Fouad; Salem, Atef; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Men; Women; Negative Images; Actors; Films; Hats; Head Covers/Veils; Fez/Tarboush; Food; Facial Hair; Costumes
  - Bedouins Love | Actors in Image: Ismail Yasin, Soad Mekawy, 1946; ref9_000002; Al Jazayerli, Fouad; Salem, Atef; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 52)
    Men; Women; Films; Negative Images; Actors; Fez/Tarboush; Head Covers/Veils; Chefs/Cooks; Costumes; Food
  - Bedouins Love | Actors in Image: Ismail Yasin, Soad Mekawy, Beshara Wakim, Abdel-Wareth Asar, 1946; ref9_000003; Al Jazayerli, Fouad; Salem, Atef; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 53)
    Men; Women; Negative Images; Actors; Costumes; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Facial Hair; Jewelry; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Paintings; Facial Hair; Facial Hair
- My Cousin and I, 1946; ref10; Hassan, Abdel Fattah
  - My Cousin and I | Actors in Image: Aqeila Rateb, Thoraya Helmy, 1946; ref10_000001; Hassan, Abdel Fattah; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Women; Actors; Negative Images; Films; Costumes
  - My Cousin and I | Actors in Image: Aqeila Rateb, Thoraya Helmy, 1946; ref10_000002; Hassan, Abdel Fattah; 1 negatives (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Women; Films; Actors; Negative Images; Food; Jewelry; Costumes; Furnishings
- Return of the Caravan, 1946; ref11; Badr Khan, Ahmed
  - Return of the Caravan | Actor in Image: Samira Kholosi, 1946; ref11_000001; Badr Khan, Ahmed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Men; Women; Negative Images; Costumes; Facial Hair; Actors; Films; Hats; Musical Instruments
  - Return of the Caravan, 1946; ref11_000002; Badr Khan, Ahmed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Men; Actors; Facial Hair; Films; Negative Images; Hats; Costumes; Arabic Writing
  - Return of the Caravan | Actors in Image: Hussein Sedky, 1946; ref11_000003; Badr Khan, Ahmed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Fez/Tarboush; Men; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Costumes; Negative Images; Films; Actors; Furnishings
  - Return of the Caravan | Actors in Image: Hussein Sedky, Samira Kholosi, 1946; ref11_000004; Badr Khan, Ahmed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Men; Women; Negative Images; Films; Boys; Actors; Costumes
  - Return of the Caravan, 1946; ref11_000005; Badr Khan, Ahmed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Men; Facial Hair; Actors; Films; Negative Images; Arabic Writing; Costumes
  - Return of the Caravan, 1946; ref11_000006; Badr Khan, Ahmed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Bicycles/Tricycles; Head Covers/Veils; Men; Women; Actors; Negative Images; Films; Costumes
  - Return of the Caravan | Actors in Image: Samira Kholosi, Mohtar Othman, 1946; ref11_000007; Badr Khan, Ahmed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Men; Women; Donkeys; Head Covers/Veils; Actors; Negative Images; Films; Outdoors; Costumes; Gloves
  - Return of the Caravan | Actors in Image: Negma Ibrahim, Hussein Sedky, 1946; ref11_000008; Badr Khan, Ahmed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Men; Women; Negative Images; Films; Actors; Arabic Writing; Head Covers/Veils; Fez/Tarboush; Canes/Walking Sticks; Furnishings
  - Return of the Caravan | Actors in Image: Samira Kholosi, Hussein Riad, 1946; ref11_000009; Badr Khan, Ahmed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Facial Hair; Men; Women; Jewelry; Actors; Films; Negative Images; Costumes; Flower Garlands/Bouquets
  - Return of the Caravan | Actors in Image: Samira Kholosi, Hussein Sedky, 1946; ref11_000010; Badr Khan, Ahmed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Men; Women; Drinks/Beverages; Actors; Negative Images; Films; Food; Books; Costumes; Furnishings
  - Return of the Caravan | Actors in Image: Samira Kholosi, 1946; ref11_000011; Badr Khan, Ahmed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Women; Negative Images; Films; Actors; Costumes; Head Covers/Veils; Paintings; Furnishings
- The Musician, 1946; ref12; Ziyada, Sayed
  - The Musician | Actors in Image: Laure Daccache, 1946; ref12_000001; Ziyada, Sayed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Men; Women; Negative Images; Films; Actors; Fez/Tarboush; Outdoors; Costumes; Gloves; Hats
  - The Musician | Actors in Image: Ahmed Allam, Laure Daccache, 1946; ref12_000002; Ziyada, Sayed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Men; Women; Actors; Negative Images; Films; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Pianos; Head Covers/Veils; Chandeliers; Boys; Costumes; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Furnishings; Children
  - The Musician, 1946; ref12_000003; Ziyada, Sayed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Women; Men; Actors; Fez/Tarboush; Negative Images; Films; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Outdoors; Doors/Entrances; Facial Hair; Palm Trees; Bags/Purses; Costumes; Hats
  - The Musician, 1946; ref12_000004; Ziyada, Sayed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Men; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Negative Images; Films; Actors; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Costumes; Facial Hair; Facial Hair
  - The Musician, 1946; ref12_000005; Ziyada, Sayed; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Fez/Tarboush; Head Covers/Veils; Facial Hair; Women; Men; Costumes; Actors; Negative Images; Films; Hats
- The Orphan, 1946; ref13; Al Jazayerli, Fouad
  - The Orphan | Actors in Image: Mohamed Amin, Madiha Yousri, Abbas Fares, 1946; ref13_000001; Al Jazayerli, Fouad; 1 negatives (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Women; Men; Actors; Negative Images; Costumes; Films; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Fez/Tarboush; Facial Hair; Hats; Bow Ties